with sales down five percent and co-ropping down fourteen percent worth noting is that we
did have a positive gross net in our base from q1 last year that also had a negative impact on the
overall quarterly growth rate core margin in q1 declined 4.1 percent this was mainly due to higher
r d investments as well as the impact of generics on the gross margin these results
were fully in line with our internal expectations and how we see 2026 p l phasing through the year
to be able to secure some positive growth momentum most importantly our growth drivers continue to
show very positive growth momentum something that vas has shared earlier on in the presentation with
growing at 34 in q1 slide 19 please what's great to see is that our continued focus on free cash
flow generation has paid off in q1 the lower core the lower core RPENC was compensated by favorable
And this brought back the free cash flow broadly in line with previous year, previous year, quarter one.
A strong cash flow continues to support our reinvestment into our business, including Bolton M&A, as well as as well as gives us the opportunity to return capital to our shareholders through dividends and share buybacks.
Like 20, please. We remain committed to our balance shareholder friendly capital allocation strategy alongside an increased R&D.
In the first quarter, we closed the acquisition and we also announced two early stage deals to support our oncology and immunology disease franchises.
On the other hand, for the return to capital return of capital to our shareholders front, we did pay nine point one billion dollars in dividend in March and April.
As previously announced. And in addition, we continue to progress with our up to 10 billion dollars share buyback program.
This program still has around six point one billion dollars remaining and is targeted to complete.
End of twenty twenty seven. Like twenty one without a move to the guidance piece.
So with our Q1 results, we are now reaffirming our full year twenty twenty six guidance.
We continue to expect twenty twenty six.
To have low single digit sales growth and low single digit decline in core operating income.